# **Siobhan Mahoney**

518-331-9169 | siobhan.p.mahoney@gmail.com | github.com/siobhanpmahoney | medium.com/@siobhanpmahoney

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated full stack developer driven by a passion for learning, dedication to producing excellent work, and a knack for taking initiative. With experience in Ruby on Rails and Javascript, web development has proven to be the perfect fit for the creativity and analytical dexterity that I cultivated throughout my experiences in media and the legal industry. In addition to my technical agility, I offer project management expertise and the ability to effectively communicate and collaborate with personnel across organizational levels, all of which have made me a valuable team member in a variety of contexts.

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Capture, GitHub | Demo

Job search resource and application tracker equipped with searchable listings and tools for organizing relevant notes and research, including a digital notepad, relevant press and news feeds, and in-app bookmarking tool.

- Modeled custom database schema and REST API with Active Record, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails
- Developed multi-route frontend using React and React Router
- Leveraged Redux and Thunk middleware to manage frontend state and asynchronous server communication
- Authenticated users at login by encrypting identifying account information via JWT
- Accessed and rendered real-time data from two third-party APIs

#### Chatster, GitHub | Demo

Online chat application featuring real-time message delivery with search and filtering tools that optimize access to chats, message history, and friends.

- Collaborated with classmate to develop Javascript/React/Redux frontend and Rails/Active Record/PostgreSQL backend
- Delivered live updates with fully-integrated WebSockets and Thunk middleware to open client-server communication
- Implemented cohesive UI and UX design strategy to facilitate navigation and access throughout application

## NYTimes NewsWire, GitHub | Demo

SPA featuring New York Times article feed with real-time updates, curated recommendations, and bookmarking tool.

- Communicated with multiple NYTimes RESTful API endpoints to render article feed and curate story recommendations
- Integrated isomorphic fetching and React lifecycle methods for real-time updates
- Engineered user interface using Javascript, React, and responsive design techniques, including CSS flexbox

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript (ES6), React, Redux, Thunk, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Active Record, SQL, Heroku, HTML, CSS, Git

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### WNET, New York, NY

Board and Legal Coordinator, August 2015 – September 2017

- Primary liaison to the 120 members of the organization's board of trustees and 10 board committees
- Improved board engagement through frequent communication about events and mission-driven initiatives
- Orchestrated collaboration among CEO, board chair, and staff to prepare materials for 60 board/committee meetings per year
- Tracked board and committee involvement and managed records of members' personal and professional information

# Boies Schiller Flexner LLP, New York, NY

Case Manager, December 2013 – August 2015

Litigation Paralegal, July 2011 - December 2013

- Established project workflow schedules, tracked deliverables, and delegated support staff assignments for team of 25 attorneys
- Influenced strategy development by performing research using legal databases, news and social media, and court records
- Led document review and production processes and served as liaison to e-discovery platform personnel

# **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School, New York, NY, November 2017 – March 2018

• Full Stack Web Development, Software Engineering Immersive Program

Fordham University, Bronx, NY, September 2007 – May 2011

- Bachelor of Arts: History and Communications
- Major GPA: 3.80